ANDY CHEN

amazingandyyy@gmail.com | 628.264.4363 | linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy | San Francisco

SUMMARY

Andy is a senior full-stack engineer turned infrastructure engineer, with proven experience of DevOps, event streaming architect, and containerized infrastructure. With user experience in mind, he built tools that will make the developer experience. Currently, he holds AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (AWS-CSA) issued by AWS and Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) issued by Linux Foundation.

PROVEN TECHNICAL SKILLS

Infrastructure	Docker/ Kubernetes /Helm, Flink /Beam/Data engineer, Kafka /stream-based architect, Protocol Buffer Data model design, gRPC
SRE/DevOps	TravisCl/Jenkins, AWS Solutions Architect, NPM/nexus, GNU make, Unix script
Full-stack	RESTful API/GraphQL API, Express, MongoDB/MySQL/PostgreSQL, React , Redux, MobX, Gulp, Webpack, RWD, TDD
Languages	Javascript, Nodejs, Unix scripts , Golang, Python, PHP, JAVA

EXPERIENCE

Minted LLC, San Francisco — Senior Infrastructure Engineer - Architecture March 2019 - April 2020

- Authored Kafka python/typescript client library and manage the AWS MSK cluster with 100 RPS.
- Owned protocol buffer development process of compiling, testing and deploying, and drove proto3 migration by leveraging prototool, Unix scripts, and dockers.
- Refactored Helm charts to scale Flink/Beam data pipeline from one to N cluster and prepared chaos engineering by enabling high availability mode.
- Improved internal tooling and speeded up Jenkins continuous testing/deployment pipelines by 5 times.

Block Node Service Inc. San Francisco — Senior Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) Oct. 2018 - March 2019

- Leveraged Docker, AWS CloudFormation to speed up the full-node initial process, successfully decrease the usual full-node hosting DevOps from 3 weeks to 15 seconds.
- Distributed stable service globally with CloudFront and Route53, successfully cut server usage by 60% and decreased responding time by 50%.
- Developed a serverless, stateless architecture to deliver the first-of-its-kind full-node monitoring service and won the top 3 as "the most fundable project" on Draper Demo day in Fall 2018.

Bodhi Foundation, San Mateo — **Senior Software Engineer**

May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Migrated the whole React UI library from redux to MobX architecture in 4 weeks.
- Built the prototype of ginfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.
- Developed and audited production-ready complex solidity smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Introduced style-checking linter and coordinated with teammates to improve the collaboration cycle and speed up the development process.

Yeah Education, Berkeley — **Founding CTO**

- Dec. 2015 April 2017
- Led a development team of 4 engineers to develop a full-stack web-based application.
- Migrated codebase from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrated existing RESTful API to GraphQL-RESTful hybrid API.
- Scaled business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

Andysign Studio, Mountain View — **Freelance Web Developer**

Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Contracted with 8 clients to develop static websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned a full satisfaction rate from clients.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley — Bachelor of Science, Cognitive Science June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental). Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

Draper University — Certificated Entrepreneur

Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Led <u>BNS</u> project and graduated as top 3 of "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day. Completed Hero Training Program and was nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper.

PROJECTS/MENTORSHIPS

NodeSchool SanFrancisco Chapter

Serve as regular monthly mentor at NodeSchool SF and Oakland chapter for more than 3 years, mentoring topics in everything about NodeJS and general software engineering.

mern - popular MERN stack application boilerplate

A MERN stack application boilerplate, built with MongoDB, Express, React/Redux, Nodejs. With continue iteration within the past 3 years, it has been one of the most popular MERN-stack starter kits on the internet.

Leptin - A PoW blockchain completely in NodeJS

Built a Proof of working blockchain completely in NodeJS, supporting mining with dynamic difficulty, wallets, transactions, using the technology of WebSocket, secp256k1 encryption.

scratchese toolchain - A javascript toolchain purely built from the ground up

A javascript toolchain purely built from the ground up, including a nodemon like NodeJS executor, a husky like git hook, a NodeJS server framework compatible with Express.